The closer you are to death. The more you realize you are alive.
Touching the Void is a documentary, action,
adventure film directed by Kevin Macdonald.
The true story of Joe Simpson and Simon Yates' disastrous and nearly-fatal mountain climb of
6,344m Siula Grande in the Cordillera Huayhuash in the Peruvian Andes in 1985.
Joe Simpson, played by Brendan Mackey.
Simon Yates, played by Nicholas Aaron.
Richard Hawking, played by Ollie Ryall.
Himself, played by Joe Simpson.
Himself, played by Richard Hawking.
Himself, played by Simon Yates.
Touching the Void is a 2003 survival documentary film directed by Kevin
Macdonald and starring Brendan Mackey, Nicholas Aaron, and Ollie Ryall.
The plot concerns Joe Simpson and Simon Yates' near-fatal descent after making the first successful ascent
of the West Face of Siula Grande in the Cordillera Huayhuash in the Peruvian Andes, in 1985.
It is based on Simpson's 1988 book of the same name.
Critically acclaimed, Touching the Void was listed in PBS's
"100 Greatest Documentaries of All Time".
The Guardian described it as "the most successful
documentary in British cinema history".
The film explores themes of rescue, based on novel
or book, sports, peru, mountaineer.
The tone is emotional.